excelitas.com 2019-07-08

# Privacy Policy | Excelitas

#### Privacy Policy

Deutsch: Sie können die deutsche Version der Datenschutzerklärung hier herunterladen und lesen.

Français: ** **Cliquez ici pour télécharger la version française de la déclaration de protection des données.

This Privacy Policy applies to the following websites. The responsible company for the websites is detailed below:

[www.excelitas.com](https://www.excelitas.com/), [www.qioptiq.com](http://www.qioptiq.com/), and [www.qioptiq.de](http://www.qioptiq.de/) sites are operated, controlled and administered by

**E** **xcelitas Technologies Corp.  
3rd Floor West  
200 West Street  
Waltham, MA 02451  
USA **

("Excelitas", "us", "we" or "our")

* * *

[www.rodenstock-photo.com](http://www.rodenstock-photo.com/), and [www.qioptiq-shop.com](http://www.qioptiq-shop.com/) sites are operated, controlled and administered by:

**Qioptiq Photonics GmbH & Co. KG  
Koenigsallee 23  
37081 Goettingen  
Germany  
an Excelitas Technologies Company**

("Excelitas", "us", "we" or "our") from its offices within Germany.

* * *

Privacy E-mail contact for Excelitas.com users:

This e-mail address will connect you to our global data privacy team, and your message will be forwarded to the responsible data privacy contact for your region.

You can write to this e-mail address in English, French or German languages.

If not detailed otherwise, this Privacy Policy is valid for all websites above, hereinafter referred to as the “Site.”

* * *

Excelitas is committed to protecting the privacy of the users ("user", "you" or "your") of its Site. Excelitas' Privacy Policy is designed to assist you in understanding how we collect, use and safeguard the information you provide to us and in making informed decisions when using the Site. This Privacy Policy will be continuously assessed against new technologies and business practices. This Privacy Policy governs data collection and usage at the Site. By accessing, browsing and/or using the Site, whether you are a "Visitor" (which means that you simply browse the Site) or a "Registered User" (which means that you have registered with Excelitas), you acknowledge that you have read, understood and agree to be bound by this Privacy Policy. The terms "you”, "your" or "user" as used in this Privacy Policy refers to a Visitor or a Registered User. By using the Site, you consent to the processing of data about you in the manner and for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy. Please read it in its entirety.

**European Data Protection Standard.**  Excelitas Technologies Corp. has locations in and operates in the European Union. To secure European data protection standards, Excelitas has agreed to adhere to EU Standard Contractual Clauses with its EU subsidiaries. Excelitas is operating along the lines of EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). All Excelitas companies follow the data protection rules of the country they are located. Personal data that has been collected in the European Union will only be transferred to countries outside of the European Economic Area if there are sufficient safeguards set up for the transfer. For example, transfers from European companies of the Excelitas group to affiliates in third countries are covered by EU Standard Contractual clauses.

**Acceptance of Privacy Policy.**  By using the Site, you signify your assent to our Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with this Privacy Policy, please do not use our Site. Your continued use of the Site following posting of changes to these terms will mean you accept those changes.

**Policies for Underage Individuals.**  We are committed to protecting the online privacy of children. We do not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children, nor is any part of our Site directed to children.

**Use of Cookies and Other Technologies.**  We may employ cookie technology to store and sometimes track information about the users of the Site. Cookies are a feature of web browser software that allows web servers to recognize the computer used to access a web site. Cookies are small pieces of data that are stored by a user's web browser on the user's hard drive. Cookies can remember what information a user accesses on one web page to simplify subsequent interactions with that web site by the same user or to use the information to streamline the user's transactions on related web pages. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can change your browser to prevent the browser from accepting cookies. If you reject cookies, you may still use the Site, but your ability to use some areas and features/functions of the Site may be limited.

We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on the Site. We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. We use session cookies to make it easier for you to navigate the Site. In addition, login areas on the Site require that your browser accept session ID cookies in order to verify that you are properly signed in. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. You can remove persistent cookies by following the directions provided in your Internet browser's "HELP" file.

We may use web beacons (small pieces of data that are embedded in images on the pages of web sites) and auditing software to track page views and entry and exit points to and from the Site. In addition, we may use web beacons, cookies, customized links and/or similar technologies to determine whether electronic newsletter(s) sent by us to those who have requested them from us have been opened and which links are clicked. Any data collected will only be used in an aggregate form and will not contain any Personal Information, as that term is defined below.

This website is using Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google Inc. ("Google"). Google Analytics also uses "cookies". The information generated by the cookie about your use of this website is usually transmitted to a Google server in the USA and stored there. On behalf of the operator of this website, Google will use this information to evaluate your use of the website, to compile reports through website activity, and to provide other services related to website activity and internet usage to the website operator. The IP address provided by Google Analytics, as part of Google Analytics, will not be merged with other Google data. You can prevent the storage of cookies by an appropriate setting of your browser software; however, please note that if you do this, you may not be able to use all the features of this website to the fullest extent possible. In addition, you may prevent the collection by Google of the data generated by the cookie and related to your use of the website (including your IP address), as well as the processing of this data by Google by using the following link ([http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en)) to download and install the available browser plugin.

This website is also using Pardot cookies. Pardot tracks visitor and prospect activities by setting cookies on your browser. Cookies are set to remember preferences (like form field values) when you return to our Site. Pardot sets first-party cookies for tracking purposes, and sets third-party cookies for redundancy. Using first-party and third-party cookies together is standard in the marketing automation industry. Pardot cookies does not store personally identifying information, only a unique identifier. The visitor cookie is composed of a unique visitor ID and the unique identifier for the Excelitas Pardot account. For example, the cookie name “visitor_id12345” stores the visitor value “1010101010”, and “12345” is the account identifier. This cookie is set for visitors by the Pardot tracking code. If the Pardot account tracks opt-in preferences, the pi_opt_in cookie is set with a true or false value when you opt-in or -out of tracking.

**Types of Information Collected.**  Through the use of cookie technology or otherwise, we may track and collect information about your computer and software when you visit the Site. This information may include: (i) your IP address; (ii) domain server; (iii) type of computer; (iv) type of web browser; (v) access times; (vi) geographical location; (vii) number of page visits; and (viii) referring web sites addresses (collectively "Traffic Data"). Traffic Data is anonymous information that does not personally identify you. However, if you submit certain Personal Information (as defined below) in connection with your accessing certain areas and functions/features of the Site, that Personal Information may be linked to your Traffic Data. Traffic Data assists us to design and arrange our web pages in the user-friendliest manner and to continually improve our Site to better meet the needs of users.

We may also collect information about any transactions carried out between you and us on or in relation to the Site, including information relating to any purchases you make of our goods or services.

In order for you to access certain areas and functions/features of the Site and register with Excelitas (become a Registered User), we may ask you to establish certain login information and provide us with information that personally identifies you, such as your name, address, e-mail address and telephone number ("Personal In-formation"). If you communicate with us by e-mail or otherwise complete online forms or the like, any information provided in such communication may be collected as Personal Information.

You may choose not to provide us with any Personal Information. In such an event, you can still access and use portions of the Site. You, however, will not be able to access or use those areas of the Site or participate in online activities that require your Personal Information.

Participation in certain online activities at the Site may be subject to additional terms, conditions and notices and such activities shall be governed by such terms, conditions and notices. In the event of any conflict, such additional or different terms, conditions and notices will prevail over this Privacy Policy.

**Employment Information.**  Through our Site, we provide access to open positions through a careers portal. This careers portal is managed by a third party. In case you submit your personal data to the portal, the third party is required to protect this information in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Policy and not to use it for any purpose other than to carry out the services it is performing for Excelitas. When you submit your credential and/or resume or inquire about careers at Excelitas via e-mail through our Site, we will treat the information submitted with the same degree of confidentiality as if you had submitted it to us via regular mail and use it only for the purpose for which such information was provided to us.

**Uses and Sharing of Information Collected.**  Except as otherwise provided in this Privacy Policy, we will keep your Personal Information private and will not share it with third parties, unless such disclosure is necessary to: (a) comply with the law or legal process served on us; (b) provide you the products, services and/or information that you may have requested, e.g. by concluding a contract with us; (c) protect our rights or property; (d) enforce our rights; (e) protect the interests of users of the Site or any other person; (f) operate or conduct maintenance and repair of our equipment; (g) detect, prevent and/or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues, as authorized by law; and/or (h) otherwise comply with applicable laws.

In general, we will use Personal Information only for the purpose for which such information was provided to us. We may also use Personal Information to (a) verify the information you provided to us; (b) provide you with the information that you have requested; (c) respond to your inquiries; (d) contact you when necessary; (e) improve your browsing experience by personalizing the Site; (f) send you information (other than marketing communications) that we think may be of interest to you; and (g) send you information about us, including information related to our products, services, programs or promotional activities, or about third-party products, services, programs or promotional activities that may be of interest to you. In the case of third party products, services, programs or promotional activities, your Personal Information is not transferred to the third party. If you sign up or subscribe to our newsletter(s), we will use your name and e-mail address to send the newsletter(s) to you.

We may also share your Personal Information with third parties that provide services to Excelitas (including handling and delivering of e-mail communications and newsletter(s), marketing, user submitted information processing and/or storage, web shop services and web site hosting and other application services) as reason-ably necessary for them to provide said services. Service providers of Excelitas who have access to Personal Information, however, are required to protect this information in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Policy and not to use it for any purpose other than to carry out the services they are performing for Excelitas.

With regard to your credit card information, it is sent directly to our payment provider who processes your online order. The credit card information is neither recorded nor stored by Excelitas, and it can only be accessed by our payment provider. Specifically, your credit card details are sent directly to Excelitas' payment provider Intuit Payment Processing over a secure SSL-encrypted connection. They are not processed on our servers at any stage of the transaction.

We may use Traffic Data and other information we obtain from cookies to analyze trends, administer the Site, improve the Site’s usability, track users’ movement, gather broad demographic information for aggregate use, and for marketing and retargeting purposes.

We may provide Traffic Data and/or other aggregate, non-personally identifying information to third parties.

Notwithstanding the foregoing, we may transfer, sell or assign information concerning the Site and your use of the Site, including without limitation, Personal Information, to third parties, as a result of the sale, merger, consolidation, change in control, transfer of substantial assets, reorganization or liquidation of Excelitas. It is against our policy to sell personal information for advertising purposes.

**Opt-Out/Discontinue.**  If you have already bought a product or service from us, or if you have chosen to opt-in, you might receive sporadic marketing communications from us. If you do not wish to receive information from us, you may "opt-out" by clicking on the opt-out link at the bottom of each of these e-mails.

Please note that if you are a Registered User you cannot opt-out from communications pertaining to the online activities for which you registered, unless your account is deactivated.

**Accessing, Reviewing, & Modifying of Personal Information.** It is important to us that any personal information provided to us is accurate. If you are a Registered User at one of our e-commerce sites, you may review, correct and update the personal information previously provided to us at any time by editing your account information on the Site by logging into your account. We will use reasonable efforts to ensure that your information is corrected or updated in our records.

**Account Deactivating.**  If you are a Registered User, you may also deactivate your account at any time by sending an email to [privacy@excelitas.com](mailto:privacy@excelitas.com). Once your account is deactivated, it will not be viewable on the Site. As with any website, even if a user deletes and deactivates the account, some information previously posted on a public forum on the Site may still be accessible by third parties. Excelitas is not responsible for the continued accessibility of the information posted by a user prior to the deactivation of that user's account.

**Contact Information, Inquiries and Deletion of Information.**  If you have any questions or concerns regarding our Privacy Policy or any questions about the security of our Site, you can send an e-mail to [privacy@excelitas.com](mailto:privacy@excelitas.com). You can also contact the competent data privacy authorities for questions or concerns.

At any time, you may ask us what personal data we have on file relating to you and the purposes for which we are using this data. You do not need to tell us why you are requesting this information. You may also request from us to not maintain such data anymore or to stop using it for a specific purpose. If we have to keep your data due to legal obligations or if a deletion is not possible due to other reasons, we will restrict the processing of your data. If the data we have is not correct, you may ask for correction of our file. Such requests must be submitted to us at [privacy@excelitas.com](mailto:privacy@excelitas.com) or via post-mail to the company responsible for the Site without incurring costs other than the basic cost of transmitting this message. We will follow your request within a month after receipt. In order, however, to guarantee the security of any personal information provided to us we will take due measures to verify your identity before providing you access. You have the right to data portability, meaning the transfer of your data to another entity in a standard, machine-readable format. This will only be done to the extent technically feasible.

**Links.**  The Site contains links to third-party web sites. These links are provided solely as a convenience to you. If you access those links, you will leave the Site. Excelitas does not control those sites or their privacy practices, which may differ from Excelitas' practices. Excelitas is not responsible for the privacy practices or content of linked third party sites and does not make any warranty or representation regarding the content or accuracy of information on such sites. Nor does Excelitas make any warranty or representation regarding, nor does it endorse, any linked third-party web sites or the content or information appearing thereon or any of the products or services described thereon. The personal information you choose to provide to or that is collected by these third parties is not covered by our Privacy Policy. We encourage you to review the privacy policy of any third-party before submitting your personal information. If you decide to access linked third party web sites, you do so at your own risk.

**Security.**  The Site has security measures in place intended to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. We use industry standard Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption when collecting your Personal Information, and we take reasonable steps to safeguard Personal Information we collect from unauthorized access or disclosure and accidental loss or alteration. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet or method of electronic storage can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your Personal Information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or from our Site, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we make reasonable efforts to ensure security on our systems.

**Notification of Changes.**  We may change our Privacy Policy at any time by updating this posting. Changes to our Privacy Policy will be effective when posted. If at any point, we decide to use Personal Information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify Registered Users by e-mail. Registered Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their Personal Information in this different manner. Unless otherwise agreed, we will use Personal Information in accordance with the Privacy Policy under which the information was collected.
